<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" 
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
     xmlns:snf="http://www.smartnews.be/snf"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>SatelliteInternet.com</title>
        <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com</link>
        <description>SmartNews RSS Feed</description>
        <snf:logo><url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/natassiacoelho-cmyk/satellite-internet-smartnews/main/satelliteinternet-logo_smartnews.png</url></snf:logo>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Best Cheap Internet Plans of 2026</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/cheap-internet/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/cheap-internet/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 17:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <div  ><p>For years, the biggest barrier to Starlink wasn’t the monthly bill—it was the $600 "entry fee" for the dish. That barrier is officially gone. Starlink now offers a $50 per month Residential 100Mbps plan that includes a free dish rental.</p>
<p>This plan is a breath of fresh air for rural residents who were previously stuck with legacy satellite providers. While your speeds are capped at 100 Mbps (and deprioritized during peak hours), it is more than enough for HD streaming and video calls. More importantly, it finally makes Starlink a "budget" option that can compete with terrestrial providers.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Pros: No upfront equipment cost, widely available, low latency for gaming.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Cons: Speeds are capped at 100 Mbps; availability is limited to areas with excess capacity.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
    <div  ><p>If you’ve ever been denied a plan because of a credit score or been burned by a two-year contract, EarthLink 5G Home Internet is your solution. Replacing older fixed-wireless options like Rise Broadband, EarthLink’s 5G service starts at $59.95 per month and offers a truly modern experience: no credit checks and no contracts.</p>
<p>EarthLink uses 5G cellular networks to beam internet into your home via a simple plug-and-play gateway. With speeds reaching up to 425 Mbps and no data caps, it’s a powerhouse for streaming and working from home without the "red tape" of traditional ISPs.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Pros: No credit check, no contract, unlimited data, easy self-installation.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Cons: Requires a $14.95/mo. modem rental and a $39.95 setup fee.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
    <div  ><p>Verizon continues to dominate the 5G space by offering some of the fastest wireless speeds we’ve seen—up to 1,000 Mbps in select areas. If you’re already a Verizon mobile customer, this is a no-brainer. You can get home internet for as low as $35 per month, which is about as cheap as high-speed internet gets in 2026.</p>
<p>Even if you aren’t a mobile subscriber, the $50 flat rate (with Auto Pay) is incredibly competitive. There are no equipment fees, no hidden "hidden" fees, and no annual contracts to worry about.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Pros: Massive speed potential, excellent bundle discounts, no equipment fees.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Cons: Top speeds are limited to "Ultra Wideband" coverage areas.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
    <div  ><p>While 5G and satellite are great for the outskirts, Spectrum remains the king of cable value if you live in a serviced area. Their Internet Advantage plan starts at just $30 per month for 100 Mbps.</p>
<p>Spectrum has been aggressively expanding into rural pockets that were previously ignored by cable companies. If you can get it, you’ll enjoy a stable wired connection with no data caps and no contracts—something we rarely saw from cable providers a decade ago.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Pros: Very low entry price, stable wired connection, no data caps.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Cons: Price increases significantly after the first year.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2020/11/cheap-itnernet-plans-and-providers.jpg" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Best 5G Home Internet Providers of 2026</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/5g-home-internet/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/5g-home-internet/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <div  ><p>5G home internet can be a good fit, but speed needs vary. For basic web browsing and email, moderate speeds (around 5Mbps) are sufficient. Streaming, gaming, and video conferencing require speeds up to 25Mbps. Consider your household size, latency, and internet usage to determine if 5G speeds (typically 25-300Mbps) can handle everyone's needs.</p>
<p>Yes, <a href="/resources/what-is-5g/">5G home internet</a> can deliver sufficient speeds for many common household activities like browsing, streaming, and gaming (with limitations based on latency sensitivity and esports). However, it generally lags behind cable or fiber optic connections in terms of top speeds. The advantage of 5G lies in its wider availability, especially in areas lacking traditional high-speed options.</p>
</div>
    <div  ><p>No, 5G home internet doesn't replace Wi-Fi. It converts a 5G signal into a Wi-Fi network that your devices can connect to, similar to a permanent in-home hotspot.</p>
</div>
    <div  ><p>5G home internet prices typically range from $35 to $80 per month. Generally, bundled plans with cell phone service are available at lower prices. For example, T-Mobile Home Internet starts at $60 per month, but bundling with a qualifying phone plan can bring the price down to $40.</p>
</div>
    <div  ><p>5G home internet speeds vary a lot based on location. Providers advertise speeds ranging from 100 Mbps to 1,000 Mbps. However, the actual speeds customers will see depend heavily on the network in a given area. For these reasons, it’s really hard to predict the speed you'll see with a given provider.</p>
<p>That said, a good indicator could be cell coverage in your area. If a provider has a reputation for a strong signal and lots of coverage, you’re more likely to have a good experience with its 5G home internet service in that area.</p>
</div>
    <div  ><p>Finding the "best" 5G home internet provider depends on your priorities and location. Here's a breakdown of which provider excels in each key area, with a recommended provider for each:</p>
<ul>
<li>Widest Coverage: T-Mobile Home Internet (Recommended for: Rural areas with few options). Does the provider offer service in your area? Check their coverage map.</li>
<li>Fastest Speeds: Verizon 5G Home Internet (Recommended for: Gamers or those needing the absolute fastest speeds). How important are absolute top speeds to you?</li>
<li>Most Affordable: AT&amp;amp;T Internet Air (Recommended for: Budget-conscious users in major cities with light to moderate usage). How important is price compared to other factors?</li>
<li>Unlimited Data: T-Mobile Home Internet &amp;amp; Verizon 5G Home Internet (Recommended for: Heavy internet users who stream a lot, game online, or have multiple devices connected). Do you stream a lot or have many devices connected?</li>
<li>Bundling: Consider your existing cell phone provider! Bundling can lead to discounts (Recommended for: Existing customers of T-Mobile, Verizon, or AT&amp;amp;T).</li>
</ul>
</div>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2022/03/pexels-william-fortunato-6393332-e1646940169946.jpg" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Amazon Leo Nano vs. Starlink Mini: Which Portable Satellite Dish Wins?</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/amazon-leo-nano-vs-starlink-mini/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/amazon-leo-nano-vs-starlink-mini/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 23:35:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body><div ><div  ><div ><p>A rendering of the Amazon Leo Nano dish, a direct competitor to Starlink's popular Mini dish for portable satellite internet. | Image by Amazon</p></div></div><div  ><p>For a long time, <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/starlink/">Starlink</a> has been the only name in town for high-speed satellite internet on the go. If you wanted to get online from the side of a mountain or the middle of the desert, SpaceX was your only real option. But that's about to change.</p>
<p>Amazon recently rebranded its "Project Kuiper" satellite venture as <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/amazon-leo/">Amazon Leo</a>, and it is coming out swinging with hardware specifically designed to take down the Starlink Mini. The most portable of the bunch is the Amazon Leo Nano, a tiny dish that makes the already-small Starlink Mini look a little bulky.</p>
<p>Since Amazon Leo is slated to launch sometime in late 2026, we haven't gotten our hands on the Nano just yet. However, we have plenty of specs to compare against the <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-mini-review/">Starlink Mini, which we've reviewed over several months</a>. Here is how these two portable heavyweights stack up.</p>
</div><div  >  <p >
    </p><h2>Portability and Design: The "Laptop" vs. the "Book"</h2>  
</div><div  ><div ><p>The Starlink Mini is usable wherever there are clear skies, and it fits easily with the rest of your travel gear. | Photo by Bison Messink</p></div></div><div  ><p>When Starlink released the Mini, it changed the game for backpackers and nomads. It's roughly the size of a laptop and fits easily into a standard rucksack. But Amazon is aiming for even more portability.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Starlink Mini: Measures roughly 11.75 by 10.2 inches. It's thin, lightweight (about 2.5 lbs), and features a built-in Wi-Fi router, meaning you only need the dish and a power source to get online.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Amazon Leo Nano: Measures just 7 by 7 inches. Amazon claims this is the most portable high-speed satellite dish ever made. It's significantly smaller than the Mini—more like a hardcover book than a laptop.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The takeaway: If pack space is your absolute priority, the Leo Nano has the edge. However, the Starlink Mini's built-in router is a huge convenience that Amazon will have to match if it wants to win the "travel light" crown.</p>
</div><div  ><div ><p>The Amazon Leo Nano is slightly smaller than the Starlink Mini, but may trade speed for the small design. | Image by Amazon</p></div></div><div  >  <p >
    </p><h2>Performance: Real-World vs. Projections</h2>  
</div><div  ><p>Speed is where the rubber meets the road. Starlink has the advantage of a massive, established constellation, while Amazon is still in the "launching" phase.</p>
<p>Starlink advertises speeds up to 100 Mbps for the Mini, but in our hands-on testing, we've regularly seen it hit between 100 and 200 Mbps, and sometimes beyond. It's surprisingly efficient for such a small device.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/amazon-leo-mobile/">Amazon is projecting speeds up to 100 Mbps for the Nano</a>. While that's plenty for 4K streaming and video calls, it remains to be seen if Amazon can deliver on those speeds once thousands of users are on the network.</p>
<p>One area where Amazon might have an advantage is its use of Optical Inter-Satellite Links (OISL). This "mesh network in space" is designed to reduce latency and keep data moving fast by bouncing it between satellites before it even hits a ground station.</p>
</div><div  >  <p >
    </p><h2>Price and Availability: The Wait and See</h2>  
</div><div  ><p>This is the biggest hurdle for Amazon Leo. You can buy a Starlink Mini today, but you'll have to wait at least a year for a Nano. The hardware currently costs around $249–$299 (though prices have fluctuated). Service plans for "Roam" users start at $50/mo for a 100GB regional plan, or $165/mo for unlimited data.</p>
<p>Pricing hasn't been officially announced, but Amazon has promised it will be "competitively priced." Given Amazon's history of subsidizing hardware to get people into its ecosystem (think Kindle or Fire TV), we wouldn't be surprised if the Nano launched at a lower price than the Starlink Mini.</p>
</div>


<div >


<div >








<div ><div  >  <p >
    </p><h2>Starlink plans and pricing</h2>  
</div></div>


</div>


</div>


<div  ><div ><div ><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"  data-width="600" data-width-mobile="600" data-load-more="" data-display-format="default" data-full-width="1"><row ><cell  width="120"><p >Plan</p></cell><cell  width="120"><p >Price</p></cell><cell  width="120"><p >Download Speed</p></cell><cell  width="120"><p >Latency</p></cell><cell  width="120"><p >Recommended Equipment fee</p></cell></row><row ><cell  scope="row" role="head">Residential 100 Mbps*</cell><cell >$50/mo.</cell><cell >Up to 100Mbps</cell><cell >30—40ms</cell><cell >$349.00</cell></row><row ><cell  scope="row" role="head">Residential 200 Mbps*</cell><cell >$80/mo.</cell><cell >Up to 200Mbps</cell><cell >30—40ms</cell><cell >$349.00</cell></row><row ><cell  scope="row" role="head">Residential MAX</cell><cell >$120/mo.</cell><cell >Up to 400Mbps</cell><cell >30—40ms</cell><cell >$349.00</cell></row><row ><cell  scope="row" role="head">Roam 100 GB</cell><cell >$50/mo.</cell><cell >Up to 260Mbps</cell><cell >&amp;lt;99ms</cell><cell >$249.99–$349.00</cell></row><row ><cell  scope="row" role="head">Roam Unlimited</cell><cell >$165/mo.</cell><cell >Up to 260Mbps</cell><cell >&amp;lt;99ms</cell><cell >$249.00–$349.00</cell></row></table></div></div></div><div  ><div ><p>Top speeds not guaranteed during peak hours<br/>*Plan not available in all regions</p></div></div>





<div  >  <p >
    </p><h2>Should you wait for Amazon?</h2>  
</div><div  ><p>If you need internet for your RV or backpacking trip right now, the Starlink Mini is an incredible piece of tech that won't disappoint. It's reliable, fast, and easy to power with a portable battery bank.</p>
<p>However, if you can wait until 2026, Amazon Leo Nano might be the better value. Its smaller footprint and potential integration with the Amazon ecosystem (and perhaps even Prime discounts) could make it the ultimate choice for casual travelers.</p>
<p>Our advice? Get Starlink now if you need it, but keep a close eye on Amazon. Competition is finally coming to the satellite world, and that usually means better prices for all of us.</p>
</div></div>


</body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2026/01/Screenshot-2026-01-06-162849.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Best Internet for Truckers: Stay Connected on the Long Haul</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/internet-for-truckers/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/internet-for-truckers/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 15:19:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <p>When you're hauling freight across state lines, your truck is more than just a vehicle. It's your office, your living room, and your bedroom. But as every driver knows, staying connected while parked at a remote rest area or a crowded truck stop is often a struggle.</p>
    <p>Public Wi-Fi is notoriously unreliable, and standard phone hotspots usually hit data caps just when you're settling in for a movie. Fortunately, mobile technology has finally caught up with the trucking lifestyle. Between high-speed satellite and nationwide 5G networks, you have better options than ever before.</p>
    <p>We've rounded up the best internet solutions for truckers to help you stream, video chat with family, and manage your logs without the constant fear of a "No Signal" bar.</p>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2024/06/iStock-2165069453.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Amazon Leo to Double Network Size, But Needs More Time to Launch</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/amazon-leo-to-double-network-size-but-needs-more-time-to-launch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/amazon-leo-to-double-network-size-but-needs-more-time-to-launch/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 23:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <p><a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/amazon-leo/">Amazon Leo</a>, the upcoming Starlink satellite internet competitor, doubles down on its plan for a far-reaching satellite network. The company received approval from the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to add about 4,000 more satellites to its already ambitious plans for 3,200 satellites,<a href="https://x.com/Amazonleo/status/2021309850710351947?s=20"> according to Amazon</a>. What it has yet to hear about from the agency is a request to extend a July deadline to launch at least half of its satellites this year.</p>
    <p>Amazon would like more time to get its fleet up and running, requesting a deadline extension to 2028 to meet the milestone. As of February 2026, Amazon has launched 200 satellites and has admitted it's unlikely to meet the goal of 1,600 by July 30, realistically expecting to reach 700 by then.</p>
    <p>It cites “unforeseeable launch delays” and issues beyond Amazon Leo’s control, such as a shortage of near-term launch availability. Amazon requests an extension or an outright waiver of the rule, given the progress it has made. <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/licensing-databases/licensing">The FCC sets deadlines</a> for certain telecommunication rollouts to prevent companies from essentially “squatting” on valuable spectrum licenses. </p>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2026/02/Amazon-Arianespace-launch-e1771458820395.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Viasat vs. Hughesnet: Comparing The Two Legacy Satellite Connections</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/viasat-vs-hughesnet/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/viasat-vs-hughesnet/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 17:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <h2>Is Viasat better than Hughesnet?</h2>
    <p><a href="/providers/viasat/">Viasat</a> and <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/hughesnet/">Hughesnet</a> are two of the three satellite internet providers available in most of North America. They're similar in many ways, but Hughesnet is better for affordable prices, and Viasat is better for its unlimited data and no contracts.</p>
    <p>Hughesnet offers the most affordable satellite internet, providing decent speeds and even a low-latency option. However, Viasat recently eliminated its two-year commitment and hard data cap, unlike Hughesnet.</p>
    <p>Viasat promises unlimited high-speed data over Hughesnet’s hard caps for priority data, so it’s better suited for working from home and streaming TV. Both have download speeds that are suitable for those living in rural America.</p>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2023/01/mother-and-son-using-tablet-and-laptop-picture-id528922090.jpg" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Best Internet Providers with No Credit Check</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/internet-no-credit-check/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/internet-no-credit-check/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <div  ><p>If you're in a connectivity desert where your only other options are dial-up or a slow DSL line, Starlink is a game-changer. Because Starlink uses a massive constellation of low-orbit satellites, it can deliver speeds that feel like a city fiber connection, even if you're miles from the nearest paved road.</p>
<p>Since you buy the hardware yourself (the $349 kit), Starlink skips the credit check entirely. They aren't loaning you the equipment, so they don't need to see your financial history. It's a pay-as-you-go model that puts you in the driver's seat.</p>
<p>Best for: Families and businesses in areas with limited internet connectivity who need high-speed, low-latency internet for 4K streaming, video calls, and everything in between.</p>
</div>
    <div  ><p>Verizon Fios is one of the fastest fiber networks in the country, but they usually insist on a credit check. However, there are two clever ways to get around it.</p>
<p>First, there is Fios Prepaid. It’s a contract-free, no-credit-check version of their service. Second, if you want their standard plans, you can often skip the credit check by simply skipping the Social Security number entry during the online checkout. Verizon will instead ask for a security deposit (usually around $250). If you pay that, they’ll set you up without a hard hit to your credit score.</p>
<p>Best for: People in urban or suburban areas who want world-class fiber speeds but want to bypass the credit check.</p>
</div>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2023/01/mother-and-son-using-tablet-and-laptop-picture-id528922090.jpg" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>How to Contact Starlink Customer Service</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-customer-service/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-customer-service/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <p>While Starlink satellite internet is designed to be easy to set up and maintain, customers may still encounter issues. Whether it's positioning the dish, experiencing slow speeds or outages, or even navigating the Starlink app, responsive support is always appreciated.</p>
    <p>As stated in our Starlink review, customer service has not been its strong point or priority, but as the internet provider has grown and seen millions of more customers over the years, its made some major improvements to support. This includes faster responses to online tickets and a 24/7 support hotline.</p>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2024/06/How-to-Contact-Starlink-Customer-Service-featured.jpg" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Starlink Mini Review 2026: Now Only $249? (Tested &amp; Rated)</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-mini-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-mini-review/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <p>After several months of discounts and deals, Starlink has settled on a $249 price point. Is now the time to get the little satellite internet dish as the 2026 travel season approaches?</p>
    <h1>Starlink Mini Review 2026: Now Only $249? (Tested &amp;amp; Rated)</h1>
    <p><a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/everything-we-know-about-starlink-mini/">Starlink Mini</a> is lightweight and even more convenient than the already user-friendly Standard <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/">satellite internet</a> equipment. When I first got my hands on the Mini, I expected a pared-down version of the Standard Starlink dish—half the size for half the performance. Instead, I was astonished by the small device's efficiency and internet speed. </p>
    <p>The Mini with a <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-roam-review/">Starlink Roam plan</a> offers reliable internet on the go, featuring speeds comparable to <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-roam-vs-residential-internet/">those of Starlink's residential</a><a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-roam-vs-residential-internet/"> plans</a>. However, a primary obstacle for most users, and one that I encountered myself, is the power situation. As a mobile solution, powering the Mini is challenging and adds cost to an already pricey device. </p>
    <p>I had the opportunity to experience the Mini's performance in both a stationary environment and while in motion. I also compare the Starlink Mini and Roam plan to <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/t-mobile-away-review/">T-Mobile AWAY</a>, a 5G mobile internet solution with similar speeds and portability.</p>
    <h3>How I tested the Starlink Mini</h3>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/03/PXL_20250305_204707533-cropped-png.webp"/>
    <p>I managed to set up the Starlink Mini in less than 10 minutes. It’s great for use anywhere there are open skies, just so long as you have a method for powering it. | Photo by Candice Garcia for SatelliteInternet.com</p>
    <p>I’m Andreas Rivera, a technology writer with a nearly decade-long career reviewing products and services. For this review, I had the opportunity to test a Starlink Mini on the 50GB Roam plan. I also compared my experience to my prior testing of the Standard Starlink dish, proprietary data on speeds and pricing, and research into the satellite internet industry and the technology that drives it.</p>
    <p>For more on my experience with Starlink's fixed, residential internet service, <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/starlink/">read my Starlink review here</a>.</p>
    <h2>Starlink Mini and Roam pricing</h2>
    <p>The Starlink Mini currently retails for $249, significantly less than its $499 debut price. Starlink will have temporary sales on equipment and has previously offered discounts on the Mini. Unlike the Starlink Standard dish, the Mini must be purchased; there's no option to lease it.</p>
    <p>The Mini is compatible with Starlink's two Roam plans. Roam Unlimited offers unlimited data, whereas Roam 100GB limits you to 100GB per month. This makes 100GB ideal for temporary use, such as a long weekend trip, while I recommend Unlimited for those who are constantly on the go. You can also put your <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-pause-standby-mode/">Starlink account on Standby Mode</a> for $5 per month, which provides unlimited low-speed internet, also making it a perfect backup internet solution. </p>
    <h2>Starlink Mini specifications</h2>
    <h3>Starlink Standard</h3>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_9559-copy-1024x683.webp"/>
    <ul>
      <li>Size: 23.4 in x 15.07 in</li>
      <li>Weight: 7 lb</li>
      <li>Current Price: $349</li>
      <li>Features: Kickstand for on-the-go setup, lightweight, improved Wi-Fi</li>
      <li>Compatible plans: Residential, Roam, Priority</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>Starlink Mini</h3>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2024/12/IMG_9563-copy-1024x683.webp"/>
    <ul>
      <li>Size: 11.75 in x 10.2 in</li>
      <li>Weight: 2.56 lb</li>
      <li>Current Price: $249</li>
      <li>Features: Wi-Fi router built into the dish, size and weight of a laptop</li>
      <li>Compatible plans: Roam only</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The Mini fits in my backpack alongside my laptop, and it's not too much heavier. In fact, it weighs just a little more than the portable power supply I carry with it. It features a kickstand that optimizes signal reception, similar to the <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-standard-vs-mini/">Starlink Standard</a>, and can be used while moving at speeds under 100 miles per hour. There are methods for setting up the dish as a permanent installation on a vehicle, but I found it worked just as well inside my car.</p>
    <h2>What speeds does the Starlink Mini get?</h2>
    <p>Starlink specifies that the Mini provides download speeds of at least 65 to 260Mbps. I found that it easily delivers speeds in this range. I tested it several times with both <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-speed-test/">SatelliteInternet.com’s speed test tool</a> and the one built into the Starlink app. </p>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-05-140134-1024x567.webp"/>
    <p>The Starlink Mini proved to show consistently high performance. It never once dipped below 100Mbps as long as I had a clear view of the sky. | Screenshot by SatelliteInternet.com</p>
    <p>It demonstrated a strong signal and consistently achieved speeds of 100 to 200 Mbps. The fastest result I achieved was 222 Mbps, even on a day with overcast skies and light snow.</p>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot_20250305-140303-461x1024.webp"/>
    <p>Starlink's internal speed test tool shows that both download speeds for Device-to-Starlink and Starlink-to-Internet were consistently in line, showing the strength of the onboard Wi-Fi. | Screenshot of Starlink app</p>
    <p>It was plenty enough speed for me to browse the web, stream music, and even watch a live stream. I could do everything with the Starlink Mini that I could with a Standard dish. Additionally, just as with the Standard, latency remained low, making page loading and streaming seamless.</p>
    <p>Upload speed lagged slightly, but it was still sufficient to work from the road. My coworker, who also tested the Starlink Mini, was able to video call me from the road. The picture and sound were high quality, with no interruptions.</p>
    <p>However, I cannot guarantee that everyone will achieve the same speeds, as Starlink's performance depends heavily on location, time of day, and network capacity. Mileage will vary, but I'm confident that most users will be able to receive sufficient speeds for most internet applications.</p>
    <h2>How reliable is the Starlink Mini?</h2>
    <p>Starlink's dishes are engineered to be intuitive to set up and use. The Mini is even more so since it's meant to be used on the go. Just like the Standard dish, the first time I set up the Mini, it took several minutes for the software to update so I could start using it. In fact, every time I break it out to connect, it usually takes a few minutes for the Mini to begin communicating with satellites. However, once it does, it maintains its connection, even if you move it around.</p>
    <p>A significant appeal of the latest Starlink hardware is that it can be used while in motion. I took it with me on a brief road trip, securing it to my dashboard and turning off my smartphone's 5G. I was able to stream my music and podcasts while driving on the freeway without interruption. My passengers could also easily connect their phones to the Mini and use the web at the same time.</p>
    <h2>How strong is the Starlink Mini built-in Wi-Fi?</h2>
    <p>The Starlink Mini's onboard Wi-Fi router eliminates the need for an external router, further enhancing the device's portability. One drawback is that it runs on the older Wi-Fi 5 standard rather than the newer Wi-Fi 6. The key difference lies in performance and the number of devices that can wirelessly connect to it.</p>
    <p>It has a single Ethernet port that could be used to connect it directly to a computer or an external router. When using an external router, you need to set the <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-router-bypass-mode/">Starlink Mini to bypass mode</a>, which effectively disables the internal router. </p>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/03/IMG_4974-1024x768.webp"/>
    <p>The Starlink Mini requires only one cable for power, but an optional plug is available to connect to a separate Wi-Fi router. | Photo by Allaina Jeffreys for SatelliteInternet.com.</p>
    <p>I recommend using an external router if you need stronger Wi-Fi, such as for better performance, extended reach, or to connect more devices. However, I found that the Mini's onboard Wi-Fi is sufficient when connecting a handful of devices. I also found it has a pretty good range—I was still able to connect my phone from up to about 350 feet away.</p>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Starlink-Mini-router-1024x684.webp"/>
    <p>For improved Wi-Fi, the Starlink Mini can be paired with a similarly compact Starlink router. | Image by Starlink</p>
    <p>Starlink recently released a Mini Router to supplement the onboard Wi-Fi of the Mini dish. While I found the Mini's Wi-Fi to be sufficient for most use cases, it uses the older generation of Wi-Fi 5. This new router implements Wi-Fi 6, which is faster, more secure, and able to connect to more devices.</p>
    <p>It can also be used as a mesh device for any Starlink version, allowing you to extend your Wi-Fi network well beyond its typical range.</p>
    <h2>How to power the Starlink Mini</h2>
    <p>A drawback of the Starlink Mini is powering the dish. It's engineered to be a more portable version of Starlink, but the satellite internet provider gives customers few options for powering the dish without investing in additional equipment. It also provides little guidance on which power source will work with the Mini.</p>
    <p>The Starlink Mini kit includes a 50-foot DC power cable and a power supply. The lengthy power cord and power supply are cumbersome and add extra weight to the whole kit. Unless you have a mobile power source, such as an RV or trailer, you may struggle to find an outlet when out in nature.</p>
    <p>The kit doesn't include the 16-foot USB-C power cable, which you'll need to purchase separately from Starlink. It requires a 100W (20V/5A) power source, so when shopping for a portable power source, ensure it meets this requirement.</p>
    <h2>Essential Starlink Mini accessories</h2>
    <p>I used the <a href="https://amzn.to/4kG0hWo">Anker 737 Power Bank</a> for the majority of my testing. It was more than enough to power the dish fully and would last about three hours when actively using it with the Mini. When shopping around for a portable power bank, those rated for at least 100W typically cost between $60 and $200. You should look for power banks designed to charge laptops rather than just small devices. Different power banks have different capacities, so I would go with one like my Anker, which gives me decent online time. I also recommend getting a power bank that displays power stats, including how much battery time is left.</p>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/03/PXL_20250305_205112465-1024x769.webp"/>
    <p>The Starlink Mini pairs well with my laptop's power bank, providing approximately three hours of uptime. Plus, it’s easy enough to carry in my backpack with the dish. | Photo by Andreas Rivera for SatelliteInternet.com</p>
    <p>Other accessories to consider include the Mini Car Adaptor from Starlink, allowing you to plug your dish into your car’s 12 to 24V auxiliary outlet (a.k.a. the cigarette lighter). It’s perfect for long road trips and also comes with the essential USB-C power cable, but it’s an extra $45.</p>
    <p>Other accessories sold by Starlink include mounting kits for your vehicle and a carrying case made to protect your Mini dish. These are for specific use cases, but my laptop backpack was enough to carry everything. In my vehicle, it was easy enough to secure it to my dashboard with some removable adhesive strips.</p>
    <h2>How does Starlink Mini compare to T-Mobile AWAY?</h2>
    <p>T-Mobile AWAY is a rival mobile internet solution that's powered by 5G. <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/t-mobile-away-review/">I tested the T-Mobile AWAY service</a> and gateway device over several weeks. Both <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-roam-vs-t-mobile-away/">Starlink and T-Mobile are reliable mobile internet solutions</a>, but they are definitely for different types of users. T-Mobile is ideal for RVs, campers, and frequent travelers who don't venture too far off the grid.</p>
    <p>My speed tests would fall between 150 and 300Mbps. It uses the same 5G network as T-Mobile's home internet, so it's available anywhere you're in range of its cellular towers. It's a more affordable, temporary mobile internet solution, and though its network spans the U.S., it still has limited reach, especially in very remote areas.</p>
    <p>While Starlink Mini has near-unlimited availability, it is more expensive in the short term due to its upfront cost. Its true appeal lies in its portability and the ability to carry it in a backpack, making it ideal for those exploring the backcountry and traveling to very remote locations.</p>
    <h2>How will Amazon Leo's upcoming Nano compare to Starlink?</h2>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2024/11/Kuiper-Mini-e1749768324613-1024x563.webp"/>
    <p>The Amazon Leo Nano is a direct response to Starlink's popular Mini, which is used for easy traveling internet. | Image by Amazon</p>
    <p><a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/amazon-leo/">Amazon announced its own competing satellite internet service</a>, powered by similar LEO technology as Starlink, and will also include a mobile option. Amazon Leo is aiming to launch in 2026 and will consist of a direct rival to the Starlink Mini called the Nano. The Nano is 7 inches by 7 inches, which is comparable to the Starlink Mini dish, which is about 11.5 inches by 10 inches. So it's a bit smaller, but there are still a few unknowns, such as whether it will have an internal Wi-Fi router like the Mini. </p>
    <p>Amazon claims the Leo Nano will support download speeds up to 100Mbps. Much lower than what the Mini is capable of, but Amazon Leo's speeds may increase over time as it launches additional satellites.</p>
    <p>Pricing and launch information have not been announced as of December 2025.</p>
    <h2>Is the Starlink Mini worth it?</h2>
    <p>The Starlink Mini is a powerful tool in a small package that I thoroughly enjoyed testing—an excellent solution for on-the-go internet that's easy to use. The barrier to entry I can foresee for most people is the high price tag. That price tag gets even higher when you consider the multiple accessories I would say are essential for the Mini.</p>
    <p>It's still a perfect companion for the backpackers, nomads, and weekend warriors who need a reliable way to get high-speed internet nearly anywhere.</p>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/03/PXL_20250305_204707533-cropped-png.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Best Starlink Deals, Discounts, and Promotions</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/best-starlink-deals/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/best-starlink-deals/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <p>Starlink satellite internet is one of the fastest-growing providers of high-speed internet access for rural and mobile users. Its low latency and wide availability make it sought after for dozens of use cases, but it’s notably been expensive to obtain.</p>
    <p>Thankfully, as Starlink has grown, it has frequently offered more and more special discounts and promotions to bring its hardware and service to more people. We monitor and report on ongoing Starlink deals, which are compiled below.</p>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/03/unnamed-2.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>How Fast Is Amazon Leo? Speed, Latency, and Starlink Comparison</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/amazon-leo-speed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/amazon-leo-speed/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <p>Formerly known under the codename <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/amazon-leo/">Project Kuiper, Amazon Leo</a> is evolving from vision to an authentic internet solution. As it develops its satellite constellation, Amazon has reportedly begun testing its system with a select few businesses. While performance reports haven't been made public, Amazon Leo claims that 1 gigabit-per-second download speeds are possible with its technology.</p>
    <h1>How Fast Is Amazon Leo? Speed, Latency, and Starlink Comparison</h1>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2026/02/G8JnhABWwAIs95P.webp"/>
    <p>A United Launch Alliance Atlas V rocket undergoing preparations to launch a batch of Amazon Leo satellites. Amazon needs dozens more launches to reach its milestones to provide reliable internet service. | Image by United Launch Alliance</p>
    <h2>The new space race to gigabit satellite internet</h2>
    <p>Amazon Leo is targeting 100Mbps to 1Gbps download speeds once it's widely available. However, it’s not alone in this race for fiber-like speeds via satellite. <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/starlink/">SpaceX's Starlink</a>, already available nearly anywhere in the U.S., is upgrading its network to support gigabit speeds. While Amazon Leo is racing to deploy its satellites into orbit, SpaceX is competing to <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-2-gigabit-speeds-available-soon/">launch its next-generation satellites</a>, which depend on the success of the company's newest rocket, Starship. Given these milestones each company is racing to reach, the first to offer 1Gbps internet speed on a wide scale could be either.</p>
    <h2>Can Amazon Leo deliver on its promises of high-speed internet?</h2>
    <p>While many details about how <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/how-much-will-amazon-leo-cost/">Amazon Leo's pay structure</a> would work remain unclear, it announced three hardware kits with varying download speeds and use cases.</p>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Screenshot-2025-11-13-155124-1024x402.webp"/>
    <p>Amazon announced that Leo's home equipment will come in three varieties with very different use cases. | Image by Amazon</p>
    <p>Amazon Leo claims that its mid-tier satellite internet service, designed for residential use, will deliver up to 400Mbps and aims to offer even faster download speeds in the future. That's already faster than what Viasat or Hughesnet offer, and 400Mbps would give even Starlink's speedy internet service a run for its money in its current stage.</p>
    <p>Panos Panay, a lead at Amazon's Devices &amp;amp; Services, demonstrated one gigabit download speed using the Amazon Leo Ultra dish in early September. This test was conducted with a single terminal connected to the network, albeit without the hundreds of thousands of other terminals Amazon plans to deploy.</p>
    <p>One advantage Amazon claims for delivering higher speeds is its integration with the company's Amazon Web Services (AWS), a cloud service used by thousands of the largest websites and companies, including streaming services, social media, and work apps. This integration will allegedly make using these services faster through Amazon Leo. Another possible advantage for pricing is the</p>
    <h2>Will Amazon Leo be worth the wait, while Starlink is available now?</h2>
    <p>Amazon Leo has ambitious goals for high-speed internet at launch. It’s hard to imagine that 1Gbps download speeds will be immediately available when the service launches, especially given Starlink’s history and the progress it has made to get to where it is now.</p>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-04-130109-1024x551.webp"/>
    <p>A chart demonstrating the rise of Starlink's median download speed and decrease of latency in the U.S. between 2022 and mid-2025. | Image by Starlink</p>
    <p>Over the past few years, Starlink's speed and latency have increased dramatically, from a median download speed of 55Mbps in 2022 to nearly 200Mbps by the end of 2025. This is due in part to advances in the company's satellite technology and the rapid increase in SpaceX rocket launches. Another thing Starlink has had to contend with and still is today is network capacity.</p>
    <p>When it first launched, only a limited number of customers could acquire Starlink, while others were put on a waitlist. Currently, Starlink controls capacity by adjusting hardware and service prices across regions. Currently, Amazon Leo is conducting <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/amazon-leo-beta/">limited beta testing</a> with undisclosed enterprises, and it’s likely that the first consumers to get their hands on it will also be limited, especially since Amazon is nowhere close to its goal of 3,200 satellites. </p>
    <p>Top speeds not guaranteed during peak hours<br/>*Plan not available in all regions</p>
    <p>Starlink remains the best option for high-speed internet in rural areas and for travel, although depending on the region, customers will be paying more or less for home internet. Only time will tell when Amazon Leo will arrive and if it will be a <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/project-kuiper-vs-starlink/">real competitor to Starlink</a> and <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/high-speed-internet-for-rural-areas/">other rural internet providers</a>.</p>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2026/02/G8JnhABWwAIs95P.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Starlink vs. Viasat: Best Satellite Internet in 2026</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-vs-viasat/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-vs-viasat/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <p>Starlink and Viasat will be at the top of your search if you're trying to choose a satellite internet provider. While Starlink is the frontrunner in terms of speed and convenience, Viasat may be a more affordable option with decent speeds. I found this out myself after using both providers for several months. I also interviewed several current and former customers.</p>
    <p>Starlink offers the fastest speeds and lowest latency among all satellite ISPs. However, Starlink's hands-off support approach may turn off some customers, and you have to pay extra upfront for Starlink hardware.</p>
    <p>"With Starlink, I'm able to do everything I need: online gaming and video conferencing," said Starlink customer Jason Astel.</p>
    <p>In early 2024, Viasat completely revamped its internet plans, consolidating them into a single offering called Unleashed. This offering offers unlimited data and no contract. While Viasat has download speeds on par with most providers, it's held back by the high latency inherent in its satellite technology and higher monthly price.</p>
    <p>"When it's tuned well, it's very reasonable," said former Viasat customer Jim Olsen.</p>
    <p>I tested Starlink and Viasat at my family cabin in rural Utah to compare the satellite internet providers. What I found was surprising.</p>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2024/11/si-starlink-vs-viasat.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>