<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" 
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
     xmlns:snf="http://www.smartnews.be/snf"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <channel>
        <title>SatelliteInternet.com</title>
        <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com</link>
        <description>SmartNews RSS Feed</description>
        <snf:logo><url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/natassiacoelho-cmyk/satellite-internet-smartnews/main/satelliteinternet-logo_smartnews.png</url></snf:logo>
        
        <item>
            <title>Starlink Mini Review: Is the Smaller, Lighter Starlink Worth It?</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-mini-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-mini-review/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 21:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body><div ><div  ><div ><p>Starlink's internal speed test tool shows that both download speeds for Device-to-Starlink and Starlink-to-Internet were consistently in line, showing the strength of the onboard Wi-Fi. | Screenshot of Starlink app</p></div></div><div  ><p>It was plenty enough speed for me to browse the web, stream music, and even watch a live stream. I could do everything with the Starlink Mini that I could with a Standard dish. Additionally, just as with the Standard, latency remained low, making page loading and streaming seamless. </p>
<p>Upload speed lagged behind a little, but it was still sufficient to work from the road. My coworker, who also tested the Starlink Mini, was able to video call me from the road. The picture and sound were high quality, with no interruptions. </p>
<p>However, I cannot guarantee that everyone will achieve the same speeds, as Starlink's performance depends heavily on location, time of day, and network capacity. Mileage will vary, but I'm confident that most users will be able to receive sufficient speeds for most internet applications.</p>
</div><div  >  <p >
    </p><h2>How reliable is the Starlink Mini?</h2>  
</div><div  ><p>Starlink's dishes are engineered to be intuitive to set up and use. The Mini is even more so since it's meant to be used on the go. Just like the Standard dish, the first time I set up the Mini, it took several minutes to update the software so I could start using it. In fact, every time I break it out to connect, it usually takes a few minutes for the Mini to begin communicating with satellites. However, once it does, it maintains its connection, even if you move it around. </p>
<p>A significant appeal of the latest Starlink hardware is that it can be used while in motion. I took it with me on a brief road trip, securing it to my dashboard and turning off my smartphone's 5G. I was able to stream my music and podcasts while driving on the freeway without interruption. My passengers could also easily connect their phones to the Mini and use the web at the same time.</p>
</div><div  >  <p >
    </p><h2>How strong is the Starlink Mini built-in Wi-Fi?</h2>  
</div><div  ><p>The Starlink Mini's onboard Wi-Fi router eliminates the need for an external router, further enhancing the device's portability. One drawback is that it runs on the older Wi-Fi 5 standard rather than the newer Wi-Fi 6. The key difference lies in performance and the number of devices that can wirelessly connect to it. </p>
<p>It has a single Ethernet port that could be used to connect it directly to a computer or an external router. When using an external router, you need to set the <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-router-bypass-mode/">Starlink Mini to bypass mode</a>, which effectively disables the internal router. </p>
</div><div  ><div ><p>The Starlink Mini requires only one cable for power, but an optional plug is available to connect to a separate Wi-Fi router. | Photo by Allaina Jeffreys for SatelliteInternet.com.</p></div></div><div  ><p>I recommend using an external router if you need stronger Wi-Fi, such as for better performance, extended reach, or to connect more devices. However, I found that the Mini's onboard Wi-Fi is sufficient when connecting a handful of devices. I also found it has a pretty good range—I was still able to connect my phone from up to about 350 feet away.</p>
</div><div  ><div ><p>For improved Wi-Fi, the Starlink Mini can be paired with a similarly compact Starlink router. | Image by Starlink</p></div></div><div  ><p>Starlink recently released a Mini Router to supplement the onboard Wi-Fi of the Mini dish. While I found the Mini's Wi-Fi to be sufficient for most use cases, it uses the older generation of Wi-Fi 5. This new router implements Wi-Fi 6, which is faster, more secure, and able to connect to more devices.</p>
<p>It can also be used as a mesh device for any Starlink version, allowing you to extend your Wi-Fi network well beyond its typical range.</p>
</div><div  >  <p >
    </p><h2>How to power the Starlink Mini</h2>  
</div><div  ><p>A drawback of the Starlink Mini is powering the dish. It's engineered to be a more portable version of Starlink, but the satellite internet provider gives customers few options for powering the dish without investing in additional equipment. It also provides little guidance on which power source will work with the Mini.</p>
<p>The Starlink Mini kit includes a 50-foot DC power cable and a power supply. The lengthy power cord and power supply are cumbersome and add extra weight to the whole kit. Unless you have a mobile power source, such as an RV or trailer, you may struggle to find an outlet when out in nature. </p>
<p>The kit doesn't include the 16-foot USB-C power cable, which you'll need to purchase separately from Starlink. It requires a 100W (20V/5A) power source, so when shopping for a portable power source, ensure it meets this requirement. </p>
</div><div  >  <p >
    </p><h2>Essential Starlink Mini accessories</h2>  
</div><div  ><p>I used the <a href="https://amzn.to/4kG0hWo">Anker 737 Power Bank</a> for the majority of my testing. It was more than enough to power the dish fully and would last about three hours when actively using it with the Mini. When shopping around for a portable power bank, those rated for at least 100W typically cost between $60 and $200. You should look for power banks designed to charge laptops rather than just small devices. Different power banks have different capacities, so I would go with one like my Anker, which gives me decent online time. I also recommend getting a power bank that displays power stats, including how much battery time is left.</p>
</div><div  ><div ><p>The Starlink Mini pairs well with my laptop's power bank, providing approximately three hours of uptime. Plus, it’s easy enough to carry in my backpack with the dish. | Photo by Andreas Rivera for SatelliteInternet.com</p></div></div><div  ><p>Other accessories to consider include the Mini Car Adaptor from Starlink, allowing you to plug your dish into your car’s 12 to 24V auxiliary outlet (a.k.a. the cigarette lighter). It’s perfect for long road trips and also comes with the essential USB-C power cable, but it’s an extra $45. </p>
<p>Other accessories sold by Starlink include mounting kits for your vehicle and a carrying case made to protect your Mini dish. These are for specific use cases, but my laptop backpack was enough to carry everything. In my vehicle, it was easy enough to secure it to my dashboard with some removable adhesive strips. </p>
</div><div  >  <p >
    </p><h2>How does Starlink Mini compare to T-Mobile AWAY?</h2>  
</div><div  ><div ><div ><table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"  data-width="610" data-width-mobile="610" data-load-more="" data-display-format="default" data-full-width="1"><row ><cell  width="120"><p >Plan</p></cell><cell  width="120"><p >Price</p></cell><cell  width="120"><p >Speed</p></cell><cell  width="120"><p >Features</p></cell><cell  width="130"><p /></cell></row><row ><cell  scope="row" role="head"><a href="https://go.satelliteinternet.com/aff_c?offer_id=3521&amp;amp;aff_id=1006&amp;amp;url_id=379"/></cell><cell >$165/mo.*</cell><cell >Up to 300 Mbps</cell><cell >Unlimited data, international use</cell><cell ><a href="https://go.satelliteinternet.com/aff_c?offer_id=3521&amp;amp;aff_id=1006&amp;amp;url_id=379">View plans</a></cell></row><row ><cell  scope="row" role="head"><a href="https://go.satelliteinternet.com/aff_c?offer_id=3521&amp;amp;aff_id=1006&amp;amp;url_id=379"/></cell><cell >$50/mo.*</cell><cell >Up to 300 Mbps</cell><cell >Unlimited low-speed data after 100GB</cell><cell ><a href="https://go.satelliteinternet.com/aff_c?offer_id=3521&amp;amp;aff_id=1006&amp;amp;url_id=379">View plans</a></cell></row><row ><cell  scope="row" role="head"><a href="https://go.satelliteinternet.com/aff_c?offer_id=2998&amp;amp;aff_id=1006"/></cell><cell >$160/mo. w/ AutoPay†</cell><cell >Up to 361 Mbps</cell><cell >Unlimited data, no hardware fee</cell><cell ><a href="https://go.satelliteinternet.com/aff_c?offer_id=2998&amp;amp;aff_id=1006">View plans</a></cell></row><row ><cell  scope="row" role="head"><a href="https://go.satelliteinternet.com/aff_c?offer_id=2998&amp;amp;aff_id=1006"/></cell><cell >$110/mo. w/ AutoPay†</cell><cell >Up to 292 Mbps</cell><cell >200GB per month, no hardware fee</cell><cell ><a href="https://go.satelliteinternet.com/aff_c?offer_id=2998&amp;amp;aff_id=1006">View plans</a></cell></row></table></div><div >
          <p >
            *
            Plus hardware, shipping &amp;amp; handling fees, and tax. Fully refundable. Depending on location, some orders may take 2 weeks or more to fulfill.
          </p>
        
          <p >
            †
            with AutoPay, taxes and fees included.
          </p>
        </div></div></div><div  ><p>T-Mobile AWAY is a rival mobile internet solution that's powered by 5G. I tested the T-Mobile AWAY service and gateway device over several weeks. Both <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-roam-vs-t-mobile-away/">Starlink and T-Mobile are reliable mobile internet solutions</a>, but they are definitely for different types of users. T-Mobile is ideal for RVs, campers, and frequent travelers who don't venture too far off the grid.</p>
<p>My speed tests would fall between 150 and 300Mbps. It uses the same 5G network as T-Mobile's home internet, so it's available anywhere you're in range of its cellular towers. It's a more affordable, temporary mobile internet solution, and though its network spans the U.S., it still has limited reach, especially in very remote areas.</p>
<p>While Starlink Mini has near-unlimited availability, it is more expensive in the short term due to its upfront cost. Its true appeal lies in its portability and the ability to carry it in a backpack, making it ideal for those exploring the backcountry and traveling to very remote locations.</p>
</div><div  >  <p >
    </p><h2>How will Amazon Leo's upcoming Nano compare to Starlink?</h2>  
</div><div  ><div ><p>The Amazon Leo Nano is a direct response to Starlink's popular Mini, which is used for easy traveling internet. | Image by Amazon</p></div></div><div  ><p><a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/amazon-leo/">Amazon announced its own competing satellite internet service</a>, powered by similar LEO technology as Starlink, and will also include a mobile option. Amazon Leo is aiming to launch in 2026 and will consist of a direct rival to the Starlink Mini called the Nano. The Nano is 7 inches by 7 inches, which is comparable to the Starlink Mini dish, which is about 11.5 inches by 10 inches. So it's a bit smaller, but there are still a few unknowns, such as whether it will have an internal Wi-Fi router like the Mini. </p>
<p>Amazon claims the Leo Nano will support download speeds up to 100Mbps. Much lower than what the Mini is capable of, but Amazon Leo's speeds may increase over time as it launches additional satellites.</p>
<p>Pricing and launch information have not been announced as of December 2025.</p>
</div><div  >  <p >
    </p><h2>Is the Starlink Mini worth it?</h2>  
</div><div  ><p>The Starlink Mini is a powerful tool in a small package that I thoroughly enjoyed testing—an excellent solution for on-the-go internet that's easy to use. The barrier to entry I can foresee for most people is the high price tag. That price tag gets even higher when you consider the multiple accessories I would say are essential for the Mini. </p>
<p>It's still a perfect companion for the backpackers, nomads, and weekend warriors who need a reliable way to get high-speed internet nearly anywhere.</p>
</div></div>


</body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/03/PXL_20250305_204707533-cropped-png.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Starlink Starts 2026 With MAX and More New Plans</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-max-100-mbps-plans/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-max-100-mbps-plans/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 23:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <p><a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/starlink/">Starlink</a> has revamped its <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-vs-hughesnet-vs-viasat/">residential satellite internet</a> plans with new names, a new tier, and new extras for more value. In addition to renaming its Residential and Lite plans to Residential MAX and Residential 200 Mbps, respectively, it has reintroduced a 100 Mbps plan in select regions for $50 per month. All three plans include unlimited data.</p>
    <p>In addition, Starlink has also enhanced its introductory Roam plan with more data for longer use.</p>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2026/01/G-p_c0OWcAAbRAi-e1768435159269.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Starlink for RVs: A Complete Starlink Roam Review</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-roam-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-roam-review/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 23:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <div  ><p>Starlink Roam starts at $50 per month and includes 100GB of data, more than enough for a long weekend on the road or camping. For unlimited data, the monthly cost is $165. However, that’s not the only cost to get Starlink Roam up and running. You’ll also pay a one-time fee of $349 for a Standard Starlink dish or $299 for the more portable Mini dish. </p>
<p>If you only use your Starlink sporadically, like for weekend trips, there is a Standby pause mode. It's $5 per month and still offers low-speed internet (0.5Mbps). You can also cancel your plan at any time for no charge and reactivate it whenever you need it again. It’s pretty convenient, considering how pricey Starlink Roam can be compared to some alternative <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/satellite-internet-vs-mobile-hotspot/">mobile Wi-Fi options</a>. Fortunately, depending on the length of your RV adventure, you can determine if the price tag is worth it.</p>
<p>Starlink offers a “trial” period of its equipment and services. After receiving your kit and activating the first month’s subscription, you can cancel within 30 days for a full refund, provided you return the Starlink equipment in an undamaged condition. There’s a retail fee penalty for damaged goods, so be extra careful with your borrowed hardware if you decide to go that route.</p>
</div>
    <div  ><p>The <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/everything-we-know-about-starlink-mini/">Starlink Mini</a> is an even more portable version of its dish, shrunken down to nearly half the size and weight of the Standard dish. It has a built-in Wi-Fi router, unlike the Standard dish, which requires a proprietary router. It also requires less power.</p>
<p>The portability comes at the cost of reduced bandwidth. It's also more expensive than the Standard dish, with a regular price of $299. </p>
</div>
    <div  ><p>While the Mini can be more convenient than the Standard, since it takes up less space in an RV, it's possible to run into difficulties if you set up camp in an area with lots of obstructions. With the Standard dish, you can set it up far away from the RV to a better position with better clearance. With the Mini, you're limited by the equipment's power cable, and the Wi-Fi signal will be muted if you move it far from your RV, unless you have a mesh router from Starlink. </p>
<p>With a reliable, portable power source, the Mini is perfect for taking backpacking into the backcountry. </p>
</div>
    <div  ><p>According to Starlink’s official specifications, Roam provides download speeds of 30–100Mbps.  However, in our testing, Starlink Roam surprised us by exceeding promised speeds at times. </p>
<p>Starlink Roam does offer unlimited data, but at a lower <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-data-caps/">data deprioritization</a> rate than its fixed residential plan. Customers will experience weaker coverage and even slower speeds than customers on the Priority plans. It doesn’t guarantee you will experience those slowed speeds, but it means you easily could.</p>
<p>If your needs merit it, you can consider investing in the more expensive tiers of Starlink Roam for higher speeds (and global coverage). However, remember that these expensive alternatives come with monthly data caps, so you must monitor your usage.</p>
</div>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/03/iStock-2160797093-e1747780052733.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Best RV Internet For Every Camper</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/get-satellite-internet-for-your-rv/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/get-satellite-internet-for-your-rv/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 23:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <div  ><p>Verizon offers the most variety and value in its hotspot plans among major carriers. It offers more data for lower prices, but only if you’re already a Verizon mobile customer. Its plans can be used with any modern hotspot device, although Verizon also sells its recommended devices on payment plans added to your monthly plan.  </p>
</div>
    <div  ><p>The device I recommend to go along with a Verizon hotspot plan is the Inseego MiFi X PRO. It’s an affordable hotspot device on a $ 9.72-per-month payment plan. It’s no bigger than a smartphone and has its own rechargeable battery that lasts up to 13 hours unplugged. It has Wi-Fi 6, which offers extended range and can connect up to 32 devices. </p>
</div>
    <div  ><p>Nearly every modern smartphone comes with a tethering feature that allows it to function as a hotspot. So why use a device and a separate plan? Phone hotspot data is often very limited, and going over your plan’s cap can result in hefty overage charges. A phone’s Wi-Fi reach is very limited and can only connect a few devices at a time. Plus, frequently using your phone rapidly drains its battery and shortens its lifespan. </p>
<p>Using your phone’s tethering to connect your laptop for a short time once in a while is fine, but for frequent travel, especially with multiple users, a dedicated device is much more efficient. It provides better Wi-Fi for better signal and more devices. Plans for hotspots are more flexible since they’re prepaid and easily cancellable. </p>
</div>
    <div  ><p>Speed - 3.5</p>
<p>According to Verizon’s broadband facts label, its hotspot service on 5G has speeds of 35–143Mbps. All of its plans, with the exception of the Essential tier, can also access its 5G Ultra Wideband service, which is located in a handful of major cities but can provide speeds up to 634Mbps. When traveling cross country, you’ll likely only be on standard 5G, and when really off the beaten path, you’ll likely use 4G LTE, which provides speeds up to 75Mbps. </p>
<p>Reliability - 3.0</p>
<p>Like all devices and services that are powered by 5G, your hotspot’s reliability and signal will entirely depend on your proximity to Verizon’s cellular towers. Luckily, Verizon’s network covers a majority of the U.S., though it’s mostly 4G LTE. Verizon doesn’t have an unlimited data option for its hotspot plans, but the tiers of data are plenty for RV travelers on a long weekend road trip. The amount of data will likely depend on your typical usage and how many passengers you have. </p>
<p>Portability - 4.8</p>
<p>Most modern hotspots are small enough to fit in your pocket, and the Inseego MiFi X PRO is no exception. It’s lightweight, no bigger than a smartphone, and has a battery life of up to 13 hours. If you’re traveling in an RV, then keeping it charged should be no problem. The strong Wi-Fi 6 of the Inseego will ensure that your RV and the surrounding campground will be covered.</p>
<p>Value - 3.3</p>
<p>Verizon Hotspots are for travelers who need a decent internet connection but don’t need or want to pay for an expensive high-speed internet solution like Starlink Roam or T-Mobile. However, to take advantage of its best prices, you’ll need to already be a Verizon customer. Its plan prices are incredibly affordable, but you need to take into account the added cost of the hotspot device. Whether you get one from Verizon or another source, any adequate device can be quite expensive. Ones with decent battery life and Wi-Fi typically cost $200 to $300, which is why I recommend going with one you can buy through a payment plan like Verizon’s.</p>
</div>
    <div  ><p><a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/go/t-mobile/mobile/">T-Mobile</a> has the most comprehensive 5G coverage of any cellular network hotspot plan. Their base plan is also very affordable, at only $10 per month for 2GB of data, and its bigger data tiers are also priced competitively. Because of its availability, we recommend T-Mobile for RV life since you’ll likely get the best coverage anywhere in the country.<br/></p>
<p><a href="https://go.satelliteinternet.com/aff_c?offer_id=753&amp;amp;aff_id=1006">AT&amp;amp;T</a> has the second-best coverage in the U.S. Its prepaid, data-only plans are a one-time purchase and an excellent option to avoid overpaying for data you won’t use. However, its highest-tiered plans with the most data are among the most expensive.  </p>
<p><a href="https://go.satelliteinternet.com/aff_c?offer_id=747&amp;amp;aff_id=1006">Verizon</a> has the least coverage but has the most affordable plans, with its Essential plan starting at $10 per month for 15GB. However, the catch is that you must be a Verizon mobile customer to qualify for the low prices; otherwise, the hotspot plans on their own are much more expensive. </p>
</div>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2023/11/Best-RV-Internet-Options-featured.jpg" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What Phone Do I Need To Use T-Satellite?</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/t-mobile-starlink-compatible-phones/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/t-mobile-starlink-compatible-phones/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 19:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <p>Starlink and T-Mobile announced the initial list of compatible phones that can send text messages via satellite connection.</p>
    <h1>What Phone Do I Need To Use T-Satellite?</h1>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/02/1734358845255-1024x576.webp"/>
    <p>Starlink Direct to Cell will supposedly be compatible with most modern cellphones and will expand its list of eligible devices. | Image by Starlink</p>
    <p><a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-direct-to-cell/">T-Mobile's T-Satellite</a> direct-to-cell service has launched, and even customers of different carriers like AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon can sign up. Whether you can take advantage of the service, which lets you send text messages when out of cellular range, will depend on your phone. </p>
    <p>T-Mobile has stated that when fully launched, direct-to-cell satellite connectivity will be compatible with most modern phones from the last four years. However, only a handful of smartphone models are currently compatible. These include some of the latest models from Apple, Samsung, Google, and Motorola.</p>
    <p>The service is currently limited to this list, though Starlink and T-Mobile say older phone models are capable of using it. However, the hardware they want to expand satellite service to must have a specific certification from the Federal Communications Commission (FCC). Both companies sent a <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/ecfs/document/104082801524379/1">letter to the FCC</a> asking for a waiver of the rule. Their central argument is the usage of direct-to-cell for emergency situations, citing its use during the Southeast U.S. hurricanes of 2024.</p>
    <p>Here is the complete list of compatible phones as of January 12, 2026:</p>
    <p>Apple</p>
    <p>Apple iPhone 13<br/>Apple iPhone 14<br/>Apple iPhone 14 Plus<br/>Apple iPhone 14 Pro<br/>Apple iPhone 14 Pro Max<br/>Apple iPhone 15<br/>Apple iPhone 15 Plus<br/>Apple iPhone 15 Pro<br/>Apple iPhone 15 Pro Max<br/>Apple iPhone 16<br/>Apple iPhone 16 Plus<br/>Apple iPhone 16 Pro<br/>Apple iPhone 16 Pro Max<br/>Apple iPhone 17<br/>Apple iPhone 17 Pro<br/>Apple iPhone 17 Pro Max<br/>Apple iPhone Air</p>
    <p>Google Pixel 9<br/>Google Pixel 9a<br/>Google Pixel 9 Pro<br/>Google Pixel 9 Pro XL<br/>Google Pixel 9 Pro Fold<br/>Google Pixel 10<br/>Google Pixel 10 Pro<br/>Google Pixel 10 Pro XL<br/>Google Pixel 10 Fold</p>
    <p>Motorola</p>
    <p>moto g play 2026<br/>moto edge 2025<br/>moto g 5G 2025<br/>moto g 2024<br/>moto g power 5G 2025<br/>moto razr 2024<br/>moto razr+ 2024<br/>moto razr 2025<br/>moto razr+ 2025<br/>moto razr ultra 2025<br/>moto edge 2024<br/>moto edge 2022<br/>moto g stylus 2024</p>
    <p>T-Mobile</p>
    <p>T-Mobile REVL 7 5G<br/>T-Mobile REVL 7 Pro 5G<br/>T-Mobile REVL 8<br/>T-Mobile REVL 8 Pro</p>
    <p>Samsung</p>
    <p>Samsung Galaxy A14<br/>Samsung Galaxy A15 5G<br/>Samsung Galaxy A16 5G SE<br/>Samsung Galaxy A16 5G<br/>Samsung Galaxy A17 5G<br/>Samsung Galaxy A17 5G SE<br/>Samsung Galaxy A25 SE<br/>Samsung Galaxy A26 SE<br/>Samsung Galaxy A35<br/>Samsung Galaxy A36 SE<br/>Samsung Galaxy A36 5G<br/>Samsung Galaxy A53<br/>Samsung Galaxy A54<br/>Samsung Galaxy A56 5G SE<br/>Samsung Galaxy S21<br/>Samsung Galaxy S21+<br/>Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra<br/>Samsung Galaxy S21 FE<br/>Samsung Galaxy S22<br/>Samsung Galaxy S22+<br/>Samsung Galaxy S22 Ultra<br/>Samsung Galaxy S23<br/>Samsung Galaxy S23+<br/>Samsung Galaxy S23 Ultra<br/>Samsung Galaxy S23 FE<br/>Samsung Galaxy S24<br/>Samsung Galaxy S24+<br/>Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra<br/>Samsung Galaxy S24 FE<br/>Samsung Galaxy S25<br/>Samsung Galaxy S25+<br/>Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra<br/>Samsung Galaxy S25 Edge<br/>Samsung Galaxy S25 FE<br/>Samsung Galaxy XCover6 Pro<br/>Samsung Galaxy XCover7 Pro<br/>Samsung Galaxy Z Flip3<br/>Samsung Galaxy Z Flip4<br/>Samsung Galaxy Z Flip5<br/>Samsung Galaxy Z Flip6<br/>Samsung Galaxy Z Flip7<br/>Samsung Galaxy Z Fold3<br/>Samsung Galaxy Z Fold4<br/>Samsung Galaxy Z Fold5<br/>Samsung Galaxy Z Fold6<br/>Samsung Galaxy Z Fold7</p>
    <h2>Interested in T-Satellite?</h2>
    <h2>How to use T-Mobile Starlink</h2>
    <p>Your phone’s Apple iOS or Android OS needs to be updated to the latest version. If accepted into the beta, you’ll receive a text message informing you you’re in. From there, you don’t need to do anything else. When out of cellular range, your phone will automatically connect to Starlink.</p>
    <p>T-Mobile also released an <a href="https://www.t-mobile.com/coverage/coverage-map?msockid=11ddb33a88e46d2b2b1da71189c96c6c">updated coverage map</a> to show where Direct to Cell is usable. </p>
    <p>Since the service is currently in beta, customers can only send text messages. Several factors need to occur for the planed voice and data capabilities including regulatory changes and more Starlink satellites launched. T-Mobile said participants in the beta should temper their expectations and expect text messages to take longer to send over T-Mobile Starlink. For the best results, users should be outdoors and point their phones toward a clear sky.</p>
    <p>For customers of AT&amp;amp;T, Verizon, and other carriers, your phone must be unlocked to use Starlink Direct to Cell. You must also download an eSIM to use your current carrier and T-Mobile Starlink. Different carriers have different rules for unlocking phones purchased through them, but typically, you can unlock phones after a certain amount of time owning them or when you finish making payments.</p>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/02/1734358845255-png.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Starlink Direct to Cell &amp; T-Satellite Guide [2026]</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-direct-to-cell/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-direct-to-cell/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:27:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <p>Mobile dead zones are quickly becoming a thing of the past thanks to innovations of direct-to-device satellite coverage, currently being spearheaded by Starlink. Since the commercial launch of T-Satellite in July 2025, the partnership between T-Mobile and SpaceX has transitioned from a high-tech experiment into a valuable feature for those who venture off the beaten path.</p>
    <p>But the story doesn't stop with T-Mobile. Starlink’s "Direct to Cell" ambitions are scaling at a pace that could change mobile technology as we know it. With recent FCC approval for thousands of new, higher-powered satellites and a growing list of international carrier partners, SpaceX is setting up a global network for both broadband internet and mobile connectivity. Recent trademark filings for "Starlink Mobile" suggest that the company may soon move beyond partnerships to launch its own independent mobile service.</p>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2025-07-23-171906.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>How to Sell or Buy a Used Starlink Kit in 2026: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/sell-or-buy-used-starlink/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/sell-or-buy-used-starlink/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 19:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <p>It’s simple to buy or sell a used <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/starlink/">Starlink</a> kit, but there are a few steps you need to follow. One thing that sets Starlink apart from any other <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/">satellite internet provider</a> is that its hardware is transferable to a different owner. Customers can sell their equipment when they no longer need it to recoup their investment, which is excellent for people who want a Starlink kit but want to save money by buying one used.</p>
    <p>I decided to swap out my <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-standard-vs-mini/">Standard Starlink dish for the Starlink Mini</a> since I mainly use it seasonally and would like to take it with me when traveling. A friend of mine was willing to trade.</p>
    <p>Giving a Starlink kit to another user isn’t as simple as handing it over. You need to follow these instructions to transfer the kit; otherwise, it won’t work, and the recipient will be stuck with inoperable Starlink equipment.</p>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/02/IMG_9362-copy.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Everything We Know About Amazon Leo’s Mobile Satellite Internet</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/amazon-leo-mobile/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/amazon-leo-mobile/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 23:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <p>Amazon is aiming to introduce its satellite internet solution for travelers, RVs, and nomads</p>
    <h1>Everything We Know About Amazon Leo’s Mobile Satellite Internet</h1>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2026/01/Screenshot-2026-01-06-162849-1024x646.webp"/>
    <p>A rendering of the Amazon Leo Nano dish, a direct competitor to Starlink's popular Mini dish for portable satellite internet. | Image by Amazon</p>
    <p><a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/amazon-leo/">Amazon Leo (formerly known as Project Kuiper)</a> is a low Earth orbit (LEO) satellite internet service aiming to directly compete with <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/starlink/">Starlink</a>, offering high-speed internet nearly anywhere in the world, including while traveling. </p>
    <p>The retail and web service giant is entering the internet industry with its own satellite-based solution, leveraging a planned constellation of 3,200 satellites. What’s noteworthy about this endeavor</p>
    <h2>What is Amazon Leo’s plan for mobile internet?</h2>
    <p>When Starlink first debuted in 2021, it was only a fixed-location satellite internet service, but it made waves with its <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-roam-review/">Roam service</a>, which launched about a year later. It allowed customers to take their Starlink dishes on the road with them and get speedy, reliable internet access from their campers, vans, or anywhere they could get a clear view of the sky. </p>
    <p>Now, Amazon Leo is hoping to be the second satellite internet service to match Starlink's mobile capabilities, with its own network and hardware.</p>
    <h2>Amazon Leo hardware comparison</h2>
    <p>Amazon Leo kicked off its rebrand announcement by revealing the three dishes it will launch its service with. Each dish directly corresponds to three of Starlink’s primary hardware offerings: a Standard dish for residential and mobile use, the Mini for even greater portability, and a High-performance version for business.</p>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Screenshot-2025-11-13-155124-1024x402.webp"/>
    <p>The Amazon Leo Pro is likely to be the go-to choice for home internet use, but it can also be used on the go like the Starlink Standard. It’s an 11” by 11” square dish capable of download speeds up to 400 Mbps.</p>
    <p>If you don’t need as much speed and want an even more portable dish, the Nano is Amazon Leo’s answer to <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-mini-review/">Starlink’s popular Mini dish</a>. It’s a 7” by 7” dish with download speeds up to 100 Mbps. </p>
    <p>Finally, there’s the Amazon Leo Ultra, which is being marketed for business use. It can definitely be mobile, since it can be fitted to trucks, trains, planes, and ships. It’s also capable of 1 Gbps download speeds and improved upload speeds, as businesses need. Pricing hasn't been announced yet, but it’s certainly going to be the most expensive. To compare, Starlink’s own High-Performance dish costs $1,999.</p>
    <h2>How much will Amazon Leo cost?</h2>
    <p>Amazon Leo has not announced pricing details, including how it will break down its service and hardware costs. It’s even unclear whether Amazon Leo plans to follow Starlink’s model of requiring upfront hardware costs or to lease its equipment, as most other internet providers do, a practice Starlink has begun in select markets.</p>
    <p>The only details Amazon provided are that it will be “priced competitively,” so it’s reasonable to assume it will be priced similarly to Starlink.</p>
    <h2>What makes Amazon Leo's mobile service different from Starlink’s?</h2>
    <p>Amazon Leo clearly shares many similarities with Starlink internet, but many details remain unknown, making it hard to contrast the two at present. They're both made possible by a constellation of thousands of LEO satellites.</p>
    <p>Starlink is already well established, with nearly 10,000 satellites already launched, which has led to considerable improvements to its overall performance. Amazon Leo’s initial goal is 3,200 satellites, but it hasn’t ruled out more in the future. As of the beginning of 2026, Amazon still has a long way to go to reach this milestone.</p>
    <p>A key difference Amazon boasts is its satellites' ability to create a global mesh to boost transmission speeds and reduce latency. According to Amazon, its optical inter-satellite link (OISL) technology can sustain consistent transmission speeds, meaning that its first wave of satellites will be ready to link up upon launch. It also claims it will leverage Amazon Web Services (AWS) to further increase speeds.</p>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2026/01/Screenshot-2026-01-06-162849.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Cheapest Satellite Internet Plans of 2026 (Under $50/Mo)</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/cheapest-satellite-internet-plans/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/cheapest-satellite-internet-plans/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <div  ><p>Starlink’s budget home internet plan is Residential Lite. For $80 per month, you can get a pared-down version of Starlink’s regular Residential plan, which offers lower-priority bandwidth but still delivers download speeds of up to 200Mbps. The catch is that Starlink Residential Lite is not available everywhere and is only accessible to those living in non-congested areas of Starlink’s network. While it continues to improve its network bandwidth, there are still select areas, especially heavily populated metropolitan areas, where a cheaper plan is not available, and Starlink may charge a congestion fee.</p>
<p>The most significant barrier to getting Starlink's affordable plan is the upfront hardware cost. The hardware most recommended for home internet, the Standard Starlink dish's regular price is $349. Starlink rents its dishes at no cost in select regions, but it’s unclear which regions specifically. </p>
</div>
    <div  ><p>Starlink has also rolled out an even more affordable $40-per-month plan, capped at 100 Mbps. This plan has even less availability and is only accessible in select rural areas, though it may expand to more regions as Starlink increases bandwidth. Starlink doesn’t list where the plan is available, so customers need to check its website to see if their address is in one of these regions.</p>
</div>
    <div  ><p>Starlink does have a cheaper plan on its Roam line of packages. It's $50 per month for 50GB of data. However, Starlink strongly discourages using a Roam package as a home internet solution, as it's meant for travel. If Starlink detects you’re using a Roam package in a single location for a certain number of days (typically 60), it can, at its discretion, charge you a fee or require you to change or cancel your plan. It’s not recommended to use Roam as home internet, as it’s also deprioritized behind Residential plans.</p>
</div>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2021/08/Pair-of-Satellite-Dishes.jpeg" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Best Farm Wi-Fi Solutions (2026)</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/best-farm-internet-solutions/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/best-farm-internet-solutions/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <p>The latest innovations in farming include sensors to monitor weather conditions, control irrigation, GPS to track the supply chain, and software to automate business processes. It all needs reliable, strong Wi-Fi.</p>
    <h1>The Best Farm Wi-Fi Solutions (2026)</h1>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/10/iStock-1148006026-1024x683.webp"/>
    <h3>Large farming operations require real-time data across extensive acreage and multiple properties. Reliable internet solutions power the technology to do it. | Image by iStock</h3>
    <h2>Can you get Wi-Fi solutions on a farm?</h2>
    <p>Modern farming is highly dependent on the latest equipment and communication tools to operate efficiently and smoothly. A reliable internet connection is essential for maintaining synchronization and delivering accurate data, with strong Wi-Fi to bridge it across the property. Whether it’s monitoring autonomous equipment, running security cameras, or managing day-to-day business operations, high-speed Wi-Fi is critical.</p>
    <p>However, establishing a connection that reliably runs throughout your properties can be challenging. You need an <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/">internet provider</a> that can deliver fast speeds in rural locations, and preferably one that provides unlimited data for a fair value. Then, you need to connect everything through a strong Wi-Fi signal, which is another challenge. Here’s what we’ve found.</p>
    <h2>Long-range farm Wi-Fi solutions</h2>
    <p>Once you’ve selected your ideal farm internet provider, you need to determine how to deploy it throughout your operation, a particularly challenging task due to the large, multi-property nature of agriculture. Here are our recommended options.</p>
    <h3>Budget: Outdoor Wi-Fi extenders</h3>
    <p>One of the simplest ways to spread Wi-Fi across your farm is to set up an outdoor Wi-Fi extender—or a whole system of them.</p>
    <p>Wi-Fi extenders pick up your existing network’s signal and boost it using an antenna built into the extender equipment. There are several types (and they’re sometimes referred to as Wi-Fi antennas, Wi-Fi repeaters, etc.), but these are the best suited for outdoor use and are typically affordable.</p>
    <p>*As of 7/13/2023.</p>
    <h3>Mid-Range: Mesh Wi-Fi Systems (Asus ZenWi-Fi)</h3>
    <p>Outdoor Wi-Fi extenders are great, but a <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/how-to-extend-wifi-signal/">mesh Wi-Fi system</a> is more reliable and better suited for businesses that require strong, far-reaching connectivity. Mesh Wi-Fi systems, unlike extenders and repeaters, broadcast the original signal from multiple points, acting as a network of routers that create a stronger and larger signal area. </p>
    <p>The Asus ZenWi-Fi system provides significantly better signal coverage over larger areas than a Wi-Fi extender can, and it’s our recommendation for the easiest and most convenient mesh system option for establishing farm Wi-Fi. The ASUS Wi-Fi 6 version is affordable and powerful enough to cover medium-sized farms, and is easily scalable as your operations grow.</p>
    <graphic src="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/10/Arystone-AryMesh-e1759956477594.webp"/>
    <h3>Arystone Hubs placed throughout large properties communicate with each other and broadcast Wi-Fi. | Image by Ayrstone</h3>
    <p>Ayrstone is a full-scale farm connectivity solution designed specifically for agriculture in rural geographic areas. It touts its easy-to-install and maintain equipment, which is fully scalable to vast properties. It offers a small suite of products dedicated to helping you establish a solid, wireless farm internet connection, including outdoor Wi-Fi hubs for extending the signal into the farthest fields, indoor hubs for connecting your outbuildings, and receivers to connect your field equipment to the network.</p>
    <p>Get Wi-Fi in your tractor cab, keep your land secure with wireless cameras, and even maintain a fleet of autonomous vehicles that are reliably connected to your network. The Ayrmesh Hubs are designed to stretch a signal for several miles with multiple hubs. Equipment is designed to be weather-resistant and capable of operating in most conditions. Additionally, its hubs are solar power-ready. The best place to start is with the Hub 2x2.</p>
    <h2>Best farm internet providers</h2>
    <p>There are several solutions for getting internet in rural locations, and the industry for rural internet has undergone considerable innovations, with one of the impressive types of providers being satellite internet.</p>
    <h3>Satellite internet - For the most remote farms</h3>
    <p><a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-vs-hughesnet-vs-viasat/">Satellite internet providers</a> have been rapidly improving and are now being used by farmers everywhere to ensure their businesses remain connected. Satellite internet is available to 99 percent of the U.S., and has proven to be a reliable connection. The three satellite internet providers currently available are <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/hughesnet/">Hughesnet</a>, <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/starlink/">Starlink</a>, and <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/providers/viasat/">Viasat</a>. Each offers business-oriented plans that provide priority service and support; however, depending on the scope of your operation, your needs, and location, a residential plan may also be a suitable option. </p>
    <p>Starlink is currently the only satellite internet provider that can be used on the move with <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-roam-review/">Starlink Roam</a>, allowing you to connect autonomous equipment directly to a speedy internet connection if Wi-Fi is unavailable.</p>
    <h3>Fixed-wireless internet - For affordable, unlimited data</h3>
    <p><a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/best-fixed-wireless-internet/">Fixed-wireless internet</a> has also been on the rise and has become more accessible in rural locations, leveraging far-reaching 5G networks. The country’s largest mobile carriers all offer internet services, with business plans and products tailored to both small and enterprise-sized companies. It’s a type of internet that’s also ideal for rural businesses when wired connections are scarce. </p>
    <p>*w/ Auto Pay and qualifying mobile plan. Regulatory fees included in monthly price for qualified accounts. See full terms.</p>
    <p>**w/ Auto Pay. Available in select areas.</p>
    <p>***Consumer data usage is subject to the usage restrictions set forth in Verizon's terms of service; visit: https://www.verizon.com/support/customer-agreement/ for more information about 5G Home and LTE Home Internet or https://www.verizon.com/about/terms-conditions/verizon-customer-agreement for Fios internet.</p>
    <h3>Fiber/Cable -Speedy internet and the preferred choice if available</h3>
    <p>Fiber is by far the fastest internet solution and is typically very affordable. It requires significant investment to build out its infrastructure, especially in rural areas. However, if it is an option for your farm, it’s a reliable and lightning-fast internet option that’s perfect for any business.</p>
    <h2>Why is reliable internet essential for modern farming?</h2>
    <p>The U.S. agricultural industry benefits greatly from implementing modern networking technology and practices, keeping farms competitive with new ways of operating the business. Whether it’s for improved security, better communication, data gathering and analysis, or automation, a reliable internet provider and network are essential for keeping businesses efficient and profitable.</p>
    <p>The latest innovations in farming include sensors to monitor weather conditions, control irrigation, GPS to track the supply chain, and software to automate business processes. Overcome the challenges of getting a strong internet connection to your farm with highly available satellite internet, reliable fixed-wireless internet, or speedy fiber and cable connections.</p>
    <h2>Getting Wi-Fi on your farm FAQ</h2>
    <h3>Can I install Wi-Fi in rural areas?</h3>
    <p>Anyone can install Wi-Fi in a rural area, but your options may be limited depending on your precise location. You can often find Spectrum in rural areas, and <a href="/resources/how-to-set-up-wi-fi-on-satellite-internet/">satellite internet can be set up</a> in 99% of the U.S., for example.</p>
    <p>If you want to convince an internet provider to lay internet infrastructure in your rural area, you can reach out to an internet service provider and offer to pay up-front for the infrastructure, or you can form a co-op and together with your neighbors split the upfront costs to get better internet options.</p>
    <h3>Why is it so hard to get Wi-Fi out in rural areas?</h3>
    <p>Internet service providers (ISPs) have to build out expensive infrastructure in order to bring internet access to a certain area, and unfortunately, because rural areas typically have fewer people spaced further apart, ISPs get much better return on investment from cities. Fortunately, with satellite internet services like <a href="/providers/starlink/">Starlink</a>, <a href="/providers/viasat/">Viasat</a>, and <a href="/providers/hughesnet/">Hughesnet</a>, even rural areas can get internet access as long as there’s a clear view of the southern sky. </p>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2026/01/si-best-farm-wi-fi-solutions-1.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Best Satellite Internet Providers of 2026</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-vs-hughesnet-vs-viasat/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-vs-hughesnet-vs-viasat/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:39:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <p>Hughesnet, Starlink, and Viasat are the best (and only) satellite internet providers in the U.S., each with strengths and weaknesses.</p>
    <p>Starlink is the fastest but most expensive, Hughesnet has good budget plans and upgraded technology, and Viasat offers unlimited data and no contracts.</p>
    <p>At SatelliteInternet.com, we specialize in helping people with unique internet challenges. We’ve spent years testing satellite internet providers, talking to customers, and studying the intricacies of rural internet. We look at the major satellite internet providers and <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/high-speed-internet-for-rural-areas/">alternative internet solutions</a> for people in rural locations. We also help travelers pick the best services and devices to <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/get-satellite-internet-for-your-rv/">stay connected from their RV</a> or <a href="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/satellite-internet-for-boats/">boat</a>. Read on to compare satellite providers and find the best option for your life.</p>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2026/01/si-best-satellite-internet-providers-2025-1.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Starlink vs. Fiber: Which is Better for Your Home in 2026?</title>
            <link>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-vs-fiber/</link>
            <guid>https://www.satelliteinternet.com/resources/starlink-vs-fiber/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:32:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><html>
  <body>
    <div  ><p>Fiber internet uses fiber optic cables to transmit data. These cables are made of super-thin glass strands bundled together. A laser at either end of the cable sends light pulses through the glass cables—this light carries the data. These pulses of light move extremely quickly and can take an enormous amount of data, so fiber is generally the fastest and most efficient internet connection.</p>
<p>There are several excellent fiber providers on the market. Which one is best often comes down to where you live—these services tend to be fairly regional, and which one is best in your area might be very different from which one is best, even a town or two over.</p>
<p>Fiber is also an excellent value for money. You can frequently find 1,000Mbps fiber plans for less than $80 per month, which is a fantastic deal—better than you'll find with any other type of internet.</p>
<p>That said, we are big fans of AT&amp;amp;T Fiber, Earthlink, T-Mobile Fiber, and Spectrum for their growing availability. Each offers excellent value, superfast speeds, and good customer support. The latter is a big deal because <a href="/resources/starlink-customer-service/">Starlink's customer support</a> is not our favorite. Its unorthodox approach to support is hands-off, including installation, if you plan to mount the dish permanently on your home. </p>
<p>AT&amp;amp;T is one of the fastest fiber internet providers in the country, with speeds up to 5,000 Mbps. The more standard 1,000Mbps plan is less than $80 per month, which is a steal. AT&amp;amp;T is also a very reliable service; we've had a great experience with it. </p>
</div>
  </body>
</html></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <media:thumbnail url="https://www.satelliteinternet.com/app/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-18-143142.webp" />
            <snf:analytics><![CDATA[
                <script>
                  (function(w,d,s,l,i){w[l]=w[l]||[];w[l].push({'gtm.start':
                  new Date().getTime(),event:'gtm.js'});var f=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],
                  j=d.createElement(s),dl=l!='dataLayer'?'&l='+l:'';j.async=true;j.src=
                  'https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id='+i+dl;f.parentNode.insertBefore(j,f);
                  })(window,document,'script','dataLayer','G-4RNELPQG75');
                  window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || [];
                  function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);}
                  gtag('js', new Date());
                  gtag('config', 'G-4RNELPQG75');
                </script>
]]></snf:analytics>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>